65. The Terracotta Army. Ying Zheng was born in 259 B.C., a time of great chaos and fighting
in Chinese history. Ying was a part of the Qing Dynasty, which united China for the first
time. Ying became the first emperor of China and renamed himself First Emperor Qin Shi
Huang. First Emperor had spent his entire life fighting, so perhaps it makes sense that
he went into the afterlife prepared to fight. When he was 13 or 14 years old, the emperor
ordered the construction of a massive terracotta army for his tomb, and he specifically stated
that no two soldiers were to look alike. Craftsmen began the great task. Arms, legs,
and torsos were made in molds and assembled later. The soldiers are all life-sized, between
5 feet 8 inches and 6 feet 2 inches tall. The faces are of eight different basic types,
which were then modified to make each face distinct. Some people believe the faces were
modeled after real Qing warriors. Their clothing and hairstyles reflect their different ranks. The
soldiers are fierce-looking and lifelike. The soldiers were placed in a massive city of the
dead that First Emperor built for himself. Around 700,000 workers built the emperor's great resting
place. The city included a palace, administrative buildings, and anything else the emperor might
need, including his army. Archaeologists have found more than 1,000 warriors so far, but they
estimate that there are 7,000 or 8,000 of them in total. There are also horses, chariots, and weapons.
The army is arranged tactically as though it is ready to spring into battle. A warrior from
beginning to end, First Emperor would not be defeated, not even in death.